tuftandneedle.com 2019-11-15

# Privacy Policy | Tuft & Needle

Current policy effective as of Jul 15, 2019

This Tuft & Needle Privacy Policy (the “Privacy Policy”) applies to our website, www.tuftandneedle.com, and any other digital properties (collectively, the “Site”) operated by Fosbrooke, Inc. dba Tuft & Needle (“T&N”, "our", “we”, or “us”). If you do not agree to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Site. The Privacy Policy is part of and incorporated into the Terms & Conditions of Service (the “Terms”).

* * *

## I. Changes to This Privacy Policy

We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time and when we do so, we will update the effective date above. We will notify you of any material changes by posting a notice on the Site and/or by sending you an email at the email address we have on file for you. You may wish to review the Privacy Policy regularly to see whether it has changed, as your continued use of the Site following a posted update will signify your acceptance of the Privacy Policy, as posted.

* * *

## II. Purpose of this Privacy Policy

The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you about how T&N collects, uses, and discloses the information collected from and about you and other users of the Site.

* * *

## III. Definitions

The following definitions apply when these terms are used in the Privacy Policy. If a term is not defined in Privacy Policy, it may be defined in the Terms.

“IP Address” refers to “Internet Protocol Address” and means the unique number that allows computers attached to the Internet to know where to send you data (such as the webpages you view) and where the data that you are sending is coming from.

“Personal Information” means information that, alone or when in combination with other information, identifies, relates to, or could reasonably be linked to, directly or indirectly, a person or household. Your Personal Information includes, without limitation, your name, address, email address, phone number, IP address, cookie IDs, and device identifiers. Your Personal Information does not include information that we obtain in or transform into an anonymous format from which a third party cannot identify you. However, if we collect Non-personal Information and link it to your full name or other type of Personal Information, the combination of this data would be “Personal Information.”

“Non-Personal Information” means information that does not identify you as a specific individual, including without limitation anonymous usage statistics including frequency of messaging and interaction with other users, clickstream data other log file data, or social analytics and tracking measurements. We may link your Non-Personal Information to your Personal Information which, in combination, would become, and would be treated as, Personal Information.

“Aggregate Data” means Non-Personal Information that we collect about a group or category of customers or Products. Aggregate data helps us to understand trends so that we can better consider new Products and services, analyze usage, facilitate payments, or otherwise improve or tailor our offerings. For example, we may collect data about the shopping habits of residents of a particular state (without linking this data to any specific Personal Information about those residents).

To "use" or to "process" information means to handle or utilize the information in any way, including without limitation by subjecting the information to statistical or other evaluation or analysis, or by collecting, storing, modifying, deleting, combining the information (including by using cookies on a computer), or by disclosing and/or transferring the information within our company or among our affiliates within the United States or internationally.

* * *

## IV. Types of Information We Collect About You

We collect Personal Information, Non-Personal Information, and Aggregate Data as defined above. The categories of information we collect from you include:

  * _Name and Contact Information_ : We may collect your name, email address, postal address, phone number, and other similar contact information.
  * _Demographic Information:_ We may collect demographic information such as age, gender, city, state, and country.
  * _Usage Information_ : We may collect data about how you and your devices interact with the Site and our related services. This could include features you use, the web pages you visit, the products you view, and the search terms you enter. This could also include data about your devices and the network you use to connect to our Site, including IP Address, device identifiers, and data about the performance of the services you use on the Site and any problems you experience with them.
  * _Content and Other Information You Provide to Us:_ We collect additional content and information that you voluntarily provide us, such as transaction information (e.g., purchase date, purchase amount, payment information) when you purchase something from us or inquire about one of our products, or content you submit when you contact us via the Site or by e-mail.
  * _Location Information:_ We may also collect your location if you choose to allow us to track your location through our Site or through other means, or if your Personal or Non-Personal Information indicates a certain geographic location. This information may help us provide recommendations to you based on your location, serve you with advertisements, or direct you to offerings that may be of interest to you and/or are marketed to persons near your location.

**A note about fraud:** T&N is aware of and concerned about identity theft and unlawful practices known as "phishing.” We do not and will not solicit or request your credit card information or national identification numbers in a non-secure or unsolicited e-mail or telephone communication. If you receive such solicitations or requests that appear to be from T&N, please contact us at support@tn.com before responding. More information is available on the Federal Trade Commission’s website.

* * *

## V. How We Collect Your Information

We will ask you to provide us with certain Personal Information when you purchase a Product from the Site or when you communicate with us about a Product that you have purchased from us. When you make a payment for a Product that you purchase via the Site, you will likely need to provide Personal Information to our third party service providers (i.e., payment processors), such as your credit card number. We may also collect Personal Information from you if you send us Personal Information in an email, via the chat functionality on the Site, or when you type information into certain fields (e.g., an email address field) on the Site.

We also collect any information that you may choose to post on or via the Site in any public posting areas, such as Postings or other feedback. If you choose to submit any such information, it will not be subject to the privacy protections set forth herein because it will be considered public information. If you do not want people to know your email address, for example, do not include it in any message you post publicly. Please be extremely careful when disclosing any information in public posting areas. We are not responsible for use by others of information that you post publicly.

We may ask you to participate in surveys or polls from time to time. If you decide to participate voluntarily, we may ask you to provide certain information, which may include Personal Information. We may use such information in any manner consistent with this Privacy Policy and applicable law.

We may also collect your location if you choose to allow us to track your location through our Site or through other means, or if your Personal or Non-Personal Information indicates a certain geographic location. This information may help us provide recommendations to you based on your location, serve you with advertisements, or direct you to offerings that may be of interest to you and/or are marketed to persons near your location.

We may also combine Personal Information with information we receive from other sources, such as joint marketing partners, public databases, publicly available pages on social media platforms and other third parties with whom we work.

* * *

## VI. Cookies and Other Similar Technologies

Cookies. A cookie is a small text or data file that is sent to your browser from a website's computer and is stored on your computer's hard drive. Most browsers automatically accept cookies as the default setting but allow you to block, delete, or pre-approve cookies. However, if you do that, certain websites, including our Site may not work fully or properly (e.g., you may not be able to access or use certain pages, features, or functionality). Some of the cookies that we use may be flash cookies/Adobe cookies, which are more persistent in nature. These cookies may not be deleted when your cookies are deleted. If you are interested in learning more about this, you should check your browser to determine where these types of cookies are stored and how they may be deleted. If you wish to block, delete, or pre-approve the use of cookies, you generally must do so on each computer and browser on which you wish to block, prevent, or pre-approve such cookies.

To facilitate the delivery of relevant content, some cookies we use are for ‘Google Analytics’. Those are used to identify how users engage with our Site and to provide us with interest and demographic information regarding Site visitors. We may also use this information to optimize marketing and refine advertising and/or programming strategies. For a complete privacy policy and instructions to “opt out” of Google Analytics’ data aggregation and usage, please see [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

Web Beacons. A web beacon is an electronic image, also called a "gif," that may be in the form of a "png" image, as well as iframe, script, input link, embed, object, and other tags that are used to track usage. We may use these web beacons on our Site to deliver cookies, to attribute sales to any advertising media or affiliate partners with whom we may have a relationship, to count visits, to compile statistics about usage, to help determine the effectiveness of promotional or advertising campaigns, and/or in emails that we may send you in order to tell if you have opened or acted on email that we have sent you.

Pixels. A pixel is a piece of code or an electronic image embedded on the Site (but ordinarily not visible to users) that collects information about users’ engagement on that web page. The use of a pixel allows us to record, for example, that a user has visited a particular web page within the Site or clicked on a particular advertisement, to deliver branded services, and/or to help determine the effectiveness of promotional or advertising campaigns.

Server Log Data. When you visit the Site, our servers automatically record information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website. This data may include information such as your IP Address, browser type, the webpage you were visiting before you came to our Site, the pages of our Site that you visit, the time spent on those pages, information for which you may search on our Site, access times and dates, and other statistics. We use this information to monitor and analyze use of the Site and for general technical administration of the Site, to improve the Site’s functionality and convenience, and to better serve our customers’ needs and preferences. We also may use Server Log Data to verify that Site visitors meet criteria that we have established as necessary before processing their purchases.

We may use advertisers, third party ad networks, and other advertising companies to serve advertisements on the Site. Please be advised that such parties may gather information about your visit to the Site or other sites (such as through cookies, web beacons, and other technologies) to enable such advertising companies to market products or services to you, to monitor which ads have been served to your browser and which webpages you were viewing when such ads were delivered. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices please visit [optout.networkadvertising.org/](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/) and [www.aboutads.info/choices/](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/). PLEASE NOTE THAT THIS PRIVACY POLICY DOES NOT COVER THE COLLECTION AND USE OF INFORMATION BY SUCH ADVERTISING COMPANIES.

As noted above, you may block, delete, or pre-approve use of cookies on your computer by adjusting your web browser settings. Such limitations, however, are not effective on mobile applications, though many applications allow users to “opt out” of certain advertisements and other features by adjusting their mobile device settings. If you are using an iOS device, you may opt out of tracking for advertising purposes by clicking on Settings → Privacy → Advertising → Limit Ad Tracking. If you are using an Android device, you may opt out of tracking for advertising purposes by going to Settings → Google Settings → Ads → Enable “Opt out of Ads Personalization.”

* * *

## VII. How We Use Your Information

We use your Personal Information (in some cases, in conjunction with your Non-Personal Information) primarily to answer your questions, to process and consummate your transactions with us, to deliver Products that you purchased from us, and try to solve any problems that you may encounter relating to the same. We use your Personal Information to personalize your experience on the Site and improve our Products and services.

By using the Site, you are authorizing us to gather, parse, and retain data related to the provision of the Site and your interactions with us.

By providing us with your email address, you agree to receive emails from us. However, we will not give your email address to another party to promote their products or services directly to you without your consent.

We may also use your information for advertising, marketing, and promotions. For example, we may use your information for generating web analytics to compile user information for marketing purposes, advertising, conducting marketing analysis, providing you with recommendations for products or services based on your profile, and promotional material planning and distribution.

* * *

## VIII. How We Share Your Information

We may share or disclose your Personal Information to the following categories of entities and for the following reasons:

  * With our affiliates, strategic partners, agents, third party marketers, or other unaffiliated parties who are offering products or services that we believe may be of interest to you or who require your Personal Information, for research, administrative, and/or internal business purposes.
  * To vendors, affiliates, strategic partners, agents, third party marketers, or other unaffiliated parties, for advertising and marketing purposes.
  * To unaffiliated third-party service providers, agents or independent contractors to, assist us in operating the Site, conducting our business, providing our services to you, and for our marketing and advertising purposes.
  * To law enforcement, government agencies, and other third parties, for complying with the law (or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary), enforcing our website policies, or protecting our or others’ rights, property, or safety.
  * To third parties as part of any direct or indirect corporate reorganization process including, but not limited to, mergers, acquisitions, and sales of all or substantially all of our assets.
  * To data aggregators and other third parties, to track and analyze information from our visitors and customers.
  * To protect against potential fraud, we may verify with third parties the information collected from the Site.
  * As otherwise described at the point of collection or otherwise pursuant to your consent.

As noted above, we may use third party service providers or vendors to help us operate and improve the Site and/or transact business (including, without limitation, maintenance services, database management providers, payment processors, or web analytics consultants, etc.). These third party service providers may also collect or have access to Personal Information from our Site. Such third party service providers and vendors are not authorized to use the Personal Information for any purpose other than to provide the administrative services for which they are responsible. Please let us know via [support@tn.com](mailto:support@tn.com) if you want a list of such third parties.

In addition, the feature of our purchase process that auto-populates addresses when you begin typing them into our order form implements functionalities that are enabled by Google Maps APIs. By using those features or functionalities, you are bound by Google’s Privacy Policy with respect to those features or functionalities. Google’s Privacy Policy can be found [here](https://policies.google.com/privacy).

We reserve the right to share with third parties, for any reason not disclosed above, any Non-Personal Information, including Aggregate Data. We may do this for any legitimate purpose, including industry analysis, and demographic profiling. Any Aggregate Data shared in these contexts will not contain your Personal Information.

* * *

## IX. Security

We take reasonable steps to safeguard your Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. As such, we cannot promise, ensure, or warrant the security of any information that you may provide to us.

We will make any legally required disclosures of any breach of the security, confidentiality, or integrity of your unencrypted electronically stored "personal data" (as defined in applicable state statutes concerning security breach notifications) to you via email or conspicuous posting on the Site as promptly as possible, and without unreasonable delay, taking into account the legitimate needs of law enforcement or any measures necessary to determine the scope of the breach and/or to restore the reasonable integrity of the affected data system.

You may have a legal right to receive any such notice in writing. To receive free written notice of any security breach, or otherwise to withdraw your consent from receiving electronic notices, please notify us at [support@tn.com](mailto:support@tn.com).

* * *

## X. Compliance with Law and Law Enforcement

We may access, preserve, and disclose your Personal Information, other account information, and content if we believe that doing so is required or appropriate in order to comply with law enforcement requests, other legal obligations, to respond to your requests, or protect yours’, ours’ or third parties’ rights, property, safety, or welfare.

* * *

## XI. International Transfer

We are based in the U.S. If you choose to provide us with Personal Information, we may transfer that information to affiliates, subsidiaries, and/or other third parties across borders, and from your country or jurisdiction to other countries or jurisdictions around the world. If you are visiting from the E.U. or other regions that have laws governing data collection and use that may differ from U.S. law, please note that you are transferring your Personal Information to the U.S., which does not have the same data protection laws as the E.U. and may not afford you the same rights as the laws of the E.U. afford you. By providing your Personal Information, you consent to the use of your Personal information for the uses identified above in accordance with this Privacy Policy and to the transfer of your Personal Information to the U.S. as indicated above, in accordance with applicable law.

If you choose to provide us with Personal Information, you agree that any dispute over privacy or this Privacy Policy will be governed in accordance with the provisions of Section XIV of the Terms.

* * *

## XII. Links to Other Websites, Including Social Media Platforms

This Privacy Policy applies only to information collected on the Site. The Site may provide links to other websites. T&N does not screen, has no control over, and is not responsible in any way for the content or privacy practices of such other websites or the persons or organizations that operate them. Likewise, no link to a third party website, banner ad, or other advertisement for a third party should be construed as T&N’s endorsement, authorization, or indicia of any T&N affiliation with such third party (or the third party’s privacy or information security policies or practices). Other websites may follow different rules relating to the collection, use, and/or disclosure of the personal information you may submit. We encourage you to read the privacy policies or statements of any other websites you visit.

The Site also may contains links to and enable interactivity vis-a-vis certain social media platforms, which may place their own cookies or similar technologies on your device and browser. We neither have influence over the Personal Information collected and processing operations conducted by the providers, nor are we aware of the full extent of Personal Information collection, purposes, or the retention periods. Further details on the purpose and scope of collection and processing by the social media platform provider can be found in the respective privacy policies of these providers, where you will also find further details on your rights and options for privacy protection. Personal Information that you voluntarily disseminate online in any public posting areas (such as a social media platform) may be viewed and used by others without any restrictions. We have no control over or liability relating to any information that you disseminate through a public posting area.

* * *

## XIII. Children

The Site does not knowingly target children under the age of 13, and T&N does not collect Personal Information from any child under the age of 13. If we learn that any such information has been provided to us via the Site, we will delete or destroy it. If you believe that Personal Information about your child or another child under the age of 13 has been transmitted through the Site, please contact us at [support@tn.com](mailto:support@tn.com).

* * *

## XIV. Business Transfers

In the event that all or part of our assets are sold or acquired by another party, or in the event of a merger, you grant us the right to assign the Personal and Non-Personal Information collected via the Site.

* * *

## XV. Access, Opting-Out and Other Individual Rights

We provide you with an opportunity to access your Personal Information to ensure it is correct, accurate and current. To do so, you may contact us at [support@tn.com](mailto:support@tn.com). Please let us know via email if you want us to delete Personal Information that we have collected about you.

If you receive a marketing email from us that you would prefer not to have received, you can use the “unsubscribe” link found at the bottom of the email to “opt out” of receiving future emails, or you can contact us at [support@tn.com](mailto:support@tn.com) to request the same. We will comply with your request. If you consent to our providing your e-mail address to a third party to receive their separate marketing communications, please opt-out of such communications through said third party.

Additionally, you have the right to: (1) request information about the categories and specific pieces of Personal Information we have collected about you, as well as the categories of sources from which such information is collected, the purpose for collecting such information, and the categories of third parties with whom we share such information; (2) request information about our sale or disclosure for business purposes of your personal information to third parties; (3) opt out of the sale of your Personal Information to third parties (from January 1, 2020, you can exercise this right through the “Do Not Sell My Personal Information” link in the footer of our Site); and (4) not be discriminated against for exercising any of these rights.

To exercise your rights, please contact us using the contact information below.

* * *

## XVI. California Privacy Rights

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits our Site visitors who are California residents to request certain information about our disclosure of Personal Information to third parties for direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please contact us at [support@tn.com](mailto:support@tn.com).

Please note that we do not respond to or honor “do not track” (a/k/a/ DNT) signals or similar mechanisms transmitted by web browsers.

* * *

## XVII. Canadian Privacy Rights

Canadian residents may access their Personal Information that is in our custody and control, subject to certain exceptions prescribed by law. To make such a request, please contact us at [support@tn.com](mailto:support@tn.com). We may request certain Personal Information for the purpose of verifying the identity of the individual seeking access to their Personal Information.

* * *

## XVIII. Contact Information

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, would like to exercise your rights, or if you have suggestions on how we might improve it, please contact us at [support@tn.com](mailto:support@tn.com) or 877-842-2586.
